I am excited uh tonight because I have a
good story to tell you. How many of you
like good stories?
>> I love good stories. And uh let me tell
you, this is going to be a good story.
This is the story of the Bible. Amen.
>> Amen. And it's a great story. How many
of you like good stories? How many of
you love good stories?
>> I love a good story. I love it.
Um, I love good stories. You guys like
good stories?
[laughter]
>> I love good stories.
And uh, let me tell you something. There
are two things I hate about good
stories. Believe it or not. Number one,
I hate when a good story takes a long
time to get started. I hate that. How
many of you like good stories? I love a
good story, man. I'm telling you,
nothing better than a good story. I I
love a good story. And the other thing I
hate about good stories is when you know
a good story gets put on pause. I hate
when a good story gets put on pause. So
what are the two things? Number one,
when it takes a long time for a good
story to start. And number two, when a
good story gets put on
>> pause. How many of you like good
stories?
>> So I know you're probably thinking,
"Pastor, you got a good story to tell
us?" We probably should like get started
because, you know, time is running out.
So uh I'm going to tell you a good
story. Amen.
>> Amen.
>> A Are you excited?
>> Amen. Let's pray. Heavenly Father, bless
us as we look at the story of the Bible.
In Jesus' name we pray. Amen.
>> Amen. So, once again, how many of you
like good stories?
>> Praise the Lord. Um, do you know that
the B that that the disciples missed the
story of the Bible?
And and it was it was only when Jesus
after his resurrection uh on this road
to Emmas with these two disciples, he
began to show them something that they
had missed because what they had missed
was the story of the Bible. And when
they got the story of the Bible, guess
what the result was? Revival,
reformation, heartburn. Heartburn. And
so tonight we want to understand the
story of the Bible. I love a good story.
So tonight we're going to look at the
story of the Bible and and and the the
the message is entitled the fourth
decree. Now we're going to start our
story in the book of Daniel. So I invite
you to turn there with me if you will.
Daniel chapter 5. Daniel chapter 5. and
we're going to look at the story of uh
Belshazar and the writing on the wall.
How many of you are familiar with that
story? All right. So, I want you to
check this out in Daniel 5 beginning
with verse one. Belshazar the king made
a great feast. Now, Belshazar is the
king of what?
>> Babylon. And Babylon is an anti-God
power. Amen.
>> So, here you have Belshazar, the king of
Babylon. The Bible says here he made a
great feast to a thousand of his lords.
and drank wine before the thousand. And
Belshazar, while he tasted the wine,
commanded to bring the golden and silver
vessels, which his father Nebuchadnezzar
had taken out of the temple, which was
in Jerusalem,
that the king and his princes, his
wives, and his concubines might drink
therein. So, what's happening here is
that Belshazar uh remember Babylon had
taken captive uh the Jews, and they had
also taken captive the holy vessels of
God. And so Belshazar takes these holy
vessels of God uh uh uh out of the place
he's holding them. And he brings these
holy vessels into uh into these chambers
because what he's about to do is
actually mock the God of heaven. All
right. Now, let's read on verse verse uh
uh three. Then they brought the golden
vessels that were taken out of the
temple of the house of God, which was at
Jerusalem. And the king and his princes,
his wives, and his concubines drank in
them. They drank wine and praised the
gods of gold and of silver, of brass, of
iron, of wood, and of stone. Now, pause
right here. Because Belshazar is really
being uh uh uh I mean, he's just like in
God's face. Let me tell you why. Because
right at this time, something is going
on outside the walls of Babylon. There
is a man by the name of Cyrus. And Cyrus
and his entire army is surrounding the
city of Babylon. But Belshazar on the
inside does not care because Babylon has
walls that are impenetrable.
It sits upon the river Euphrates.
And Belshazar is basically not only
mocking God, but mocking Cyrus. You're
not going to be able to get in here.
This city is too well fortified. Uh they
were in fact trying to lay a siege
around Babylon. But Babylon had enough
supplies to outlast their siege.
And so Belshazar secure in his domain is
mocking the God of heaven. But he
doesn't know something about Cyrus. Let
me share with you. Go with me if you
will. Hold your place here in Daniel.
We're going to go over to the book of
Isaiah chapter 44. We're going to read
something about Cyrus. Isaiah, excuse
[clears throat] me, chapter 44.
A and let's see what the Bible tells us
here. Isaiah 44,
uh, beginning with verse 27. Isaiah
44:27.
Uh, let's go back up to verse 26. And
the Bible says that confirmth the word
of his servant that performth the
council of his messengers that saith to
Jerusalem thou shalt be inhabited and to
the cities of Judah you shall be built
and I will raise up the decayed places
thereof that saith to the deep be dry
and I will dry up thy rivers that saith
of Cyrus
he is my shepherd and shall perform all
my pleasure even saying to Jerusalem
thou shalt be built and to the temple
thy foundation shall be laid. Chapter
45. Thus sayith the Lord to his anointed
to Cyrus whose right hand I have holden
to subdue nations before him. I will
loose the loins of kings to open before
him the two leaved gates and the gates
shall not be shut.
It had been prophesied of Cyrus that he
would open the gates that protected the
city of Babylon. The two leave gates.
The Bible says that Cyrus
would dry up the deep and in essence
enter Babylon and allow God's people,
the Jews, to be set free.
Well, this is exactly what happens
because as the story goes, one of
Cyrus's favorite horses, in fact his
favorite horse, drowned in the river
Euphrates. And he was so angry with the
river that he decided to dry up the
deep.
>> And so they began to build, you know,
put rocks into the into the rivers to
divert the waters. And when they did
this, they discovered that the gates had
been left unlocked.
And so Cyrus and his army marched in the
riverbed. They in essence descended into
the deep was what we just read. and
marched under the marched it through the
riverbed, opened up the gates and
entered into the city, the city that
that the king of Babylon thought was
secure. And so go back with me because
just at the time that this is happening,
notice with me Daniel chapter 5. We're
going back to Daniel chapter 5. And I
want you to notice what happens here.
Verse 5. In the same hour came forth
fingers of a man's hand and wrote over
against the candlestick upon the plaster
of the wall of the king's palace. And
the king saw the part of the hand that
wrote. And you remember the Bible says
the king's countenance uh changed and
his loins were loosed.
Ah man, I don't know if you know what
that means. His loins were loosed.
But don't dwell too long on that. Put it
this way, he was really scared and and
lost function
of himself.
A and his loins were loose, the Bible
says, and his KNEES SMOKE ONE to
another.
Oh boy, that that's that he's scared.
>> He's scared. A and so and so he doesn't
understand what what's going on, what
this writing is. So he calls in Daniel,
right? And and notice what Daniel says.
Go over with me Daniel 5 verse 25.
Daniel is going to tell him what was
written because he doesn't understand
the writing. And it says this. This is
the writing that is written. Many men
you faren. This is the interpretation of
the thing. Many God has numbered thy
kingdom. And what?
>> And what?
>> Finished it. Tequel. Thou art weighed in
the balance and art found wanting.
Perez. Thy kingdom is divided and given
to the Mes and the Persians.
Cyrus that night overthrows Babylon. Now
turn with me in your Bibles to the book
of 2 Chronicles chapter 36. What book
are we going to?
>> 2 Chronicles chapter 36.
When you get there, say amen.
>> 2 Chronicles chapter 36. And we're going
to take a look at verses 22 and 23. Now
in the first year of Cyrus, king of
Persia, the word of the Lord spoken by
the mouth of Jeremiah might be
accomplished. The Lord stirred up the
spirit of Cyrus, king of Persia, that he
made a proclamation, a what everyone?
Proclamation throughout all his kingdom,
and put it also in writing, saying,
"Thus saith Cyrus, king of Persia, all
the kingdoms of the earth has the Lord
God of heaven given me, and has charged
me to build him a house in Jerusalem,
which is in Judah. Who is there among
you of all his people? The Lord his God
be with him. And let him do what?
>> Let him go up. Let him go up.
There's the story.
>> There's the story.
[sighs and gasps]
Where do I begin?
Babylon is an anti-God power. And right
now you may be asking, "Pastor, um, I
know what you've been telling us, that
Christ
is in
all the scriptures."
I want you to check this out. Babylon.
Satan.
Did you know that
Babylon is really run by Satan?
>> The king of Babylon
is none other than Satan himself.
>> Yes. Amen.
>> So, I want you to take this story and I
want you to ask yourself, is there was
there ever a time that the true king of
Babylon
took something that belonged to the God
of heaven and decided to mock it or him
>> in front of the watching universe.
>> That person would be none other than
Jesus Christ.
Now I want you to remember this because
as as as Neb as as Belshazar is mocking,
he believes that his kingdom is secure.
As Satan is mocking Jesus before the
watching universe, he thinks that he has
Jesus beat.
But little does he realize something.
You see, Satan is marching Jesus
outside
the walls of Jerusalem.
>> Which means Jesus
is going outside the city walls.
The city walls.
>> Oh, you're not feeling me.
Little does Satan realize that the man
who HE IS MARCHING OUTSIDE THE city
walls
was NONE OTHER THAN A TYPE of Cyrus.
Okay.
Do you remember when we were reading
about Cyrus just now and the Bible says
uh of Cyrus that he was God's anointed?
>> Yeah. Do you realize that that word
anointed means Messiah? Cyrus was not
the Messiah.
HE WAS HE WAS CALLED GOD'S ANOINTED. BUT
WHAT CYRUS was to do would be a symbol
or a type of what Jesus Christ himself
was to do. So you say, "Pastor, what do
you mean?" Remember what Cyrus did?
Cyrus
was going to penetrate
the domain of the enemy.
And the way he was going TO DO IT WAS BY
DESCENDING into the deep. Huh?
>> [laughter]
>> JUST AS CYRUS DRIED UP THE DEEP AND
DESCENDED AS IT were and opened the
gates,
>> so Jesus Christ, the man who WAS BEING
CRUCIFIED OUTSIDE THE CITY WALLS OF
JERUSALEM,
descended into the domain of the enemy,
that in so-called impenetrable
domain
dried up the deep
in order to set the captives
>> free.
>> But wait, there's more.
Because remember when when when when
when
uh Belshazar sees this writing on the
wall, this invisible hand, part of the
words that were written were these.
It is finished.
>> Your kingdom
Belar
is finished. It was the death nail AND
AND WALK. WOW. YOU KNOW WHAT I'M
THINKING ABOUT RIGHT NOW? WHEN CHRIST
DIED UPON THE CROSS,
>> he cried out,
>> "It is finished."
>> Amen.
>> You might remember there was an unseen
hand.
>> Do you realize when Jesus died, there
was an unseen hand
>> that rent the veil in the temple? Amen.
>> I want you to listen to these words.
Bible commentary volume 5, page 1, 109.
Listen what it says. It was not the hand
of the priest that rent from top to
bottom the gorgeous veil that divided
the holy from the most holy place. It
was the hand of God. When Christ cried
out, "It is finished," the holy watcher
that was an unseen guest at Belshazar's
feast
>> pronounced the Jewish nation to be a
nation unchurched. The same hand that
traced on the wall THE CHARACTERS THAT
RECORDED BELSHAZAR'S doom and the end of
the Babylonian kingdom rent the veil of
the temple from top to bottom.
What are the odds that SHE WOULD COMPARE
THAT incident at the cross with what
happened?
>> Uh there was a
you remember when Jesus died, right? And
and there was a Roman seal put upon his
tomb to make sure
that the gate of death would not be
opened.
>> See, Rome's seal was really a symbol of
a much greater seal, Satan seal. And a
seal means do not touch, do not move, do
not disturb, do not change. MAKE SURE
CHRIST STAYS IN THE TOMB.
It was as though Satan was saying, "MAKE
SURE HE STAYS IN THE TOMB.
SO SEAL THAT SEAL WITH A Roman seal. So
you know what I like? I like how in
Matthew 28:1 the Bible says because a
seal represents authority, right?
>> So Satan's authority, keep him in the
tomb. You remember Rome is a symbol of
Satan in the book of Revelation.
>> Keep him in the tomb. So the angel
descends early Sunday morning and he
looks at the seal of authority. Oh, is
this your seal of authority? Yeah. And
he rolls it out the way.
And to add insult to injury, he sits on
signaling THE POWER AND AUTHORITY OF
HEAVEN OVER THE GATES OF DEATH and hell.
>> SO CHRIST, BELOVED, OPENED UP THE GATES
THAT his people might be set free. SO
THE QUESTION I HAVE FOR us today is, why
are we still living in the tomb
>> as if the stone is still there?
Beloved, LISTEN TO ME. CHRIST HAS NOT
SET US free just so that we can go about
our business.
>> No, no, no, no, no. You see, when Cyrus
had set the captives free, he set them
free to do something. And that something
WAS TO GO BACK TO Jerusalem to rebuild
God's city.
>> Oh. Oh. Oh. Oh. Did you Did you
>> There was a mission. There was a
purpose.
>> What was that mission? Listen, remember
how we read in 2 Chronicles how he made
this this decree? Well, the decree is
actually found in the next book of the
Bible, which is the book of Ezra. Can
you turn there with me? Go with me
quickly if you will. Book of Ezra.
Ezra. And we're going to look at Ezra
chapter uh chapter 1. And uh let's look
at verse Ezra chapter 1. And we're going
to take a look at verse uh 1-3. Ezra
chapter 1. Now in the first year of
Cyrus, king of Persia, that the word of
the Lord might be fulfilled by the mouth
uh spoken of by Jeremiah the prophet
might be fulfilled. The Lord stirred up
the spirit of Cyrus, king of Persia. He
makes this decree under this decree. Uh
this decree, listen carefully, this
decree was designed uh to allow the
children of Israel to return to
Jerusalem to build the temple. To build
the what, everyone?
>> The temple. Okay. That's all the focus
was on.
I'm sorry. Yeah. Yeah. to build the
temple. That's right. Now, there was
another decree given. Did you know that
>> this decree was given by Cyrus, but
there was a second decree given, and by
the way, under this decree, 50,000 Jews
left Babylon to go build the temple.
There was another decree also found in
the book of Ezra. That decree was given
by Darius. And this decree was against
the enemies of God's people who were
trying to stop them from rebuilding the
temple. But there was a third decree
that was given in the same book, Ezra.
And this decree was given by Arda Xerxes
in 457 BC.
This decree uh uh dealt with not just
the temple but also the city and it also
gave Israel autonomy as its own
independent country nation again. Are
you with me so far?
>> This is all in what book everyone?
>> The book of Ezra. Now there was one more
decree. Did you know that this decree is
found in the next book of the Bible
which is the book of Nehemiah?
Nehemiah was given a final decree and
this was also by artist Xerxes. It was
about 13 years later and the reason why
is this because the work that had been
done under uh the first three decrees
was incomplete. So Nehemiah had to come
along and and he saw that the work was
not finished and he gets a final decree
from Artis Xerxes. He goes to Jerusalem
to He goes back to Jerusalem to help
rebuild uh specifically the wall and the
streets.
And these are the four decrees. In fact,
Nehemiah when he got to Jerusalem said,
"Listen," he told the Jews, "Don't you
know that as long as this h our work
lays desolate, we are a reproach to God?
Let us rise up and finish the work."
Church, we got to get it together.
>> Amen.
>> And somebody say with me. Let's say I
want you to say, "Let's get it to
together." We need to get it together.
How many of you believe we need to get
it together?
>> All right. I love a good story.
>> But you know what I hate about good
stories? I hate when good stories get
put on pause.
>> And right now, we're going to put this
story on pause. So, just pause right
there. Where are we pausing? What book
are we in?
>> Nehemiah. Let's pause right here. Now, I
want to tell you another story.
It's the story of the Bible.
It's an amazing story. But to tell you
the story of the Bible, we have to go to
the book of Genesis. So, are you ready
to go to the book of Genesis? Don't turn
in your Bibles. Just focus on me.
>> All right. So, where are we going,
everyone?
>> Genesis.
>> Genesis. All right. Very good. Now, the
book of Genesis introduces us to a man
by the name of Adam.
>> Amen. The book of Genesis introduces us
to the creation of man, Adam. But the
Bible says that Adam is actually the
first Adam. Did you know that Jesus
Christ
>> was a second Adam?
>> Amen.
>> So, so you have in the book of Genesis,
you have the genesis of the first man,
but actually the genesis of the first
man is kind of like a similar type of
the genesis of the second Adam.
Amen.
>> Anybody excited?
>> Not really. Right.
>> It's like, okay. What book comes after
Genesis?
>> Exodus.
>> Exodus. Do you know that the book of
Exodus is about a man who was drawn out
of waters, goes into the wilderness for
40 years and then returns to deliver his
people. That's very interesting because
the second Adam, Jesus Christ, was also
drawn out of waters at his baptism, went
into the wilderness for 40 days and then
returned to deliver his people.
>> What book comes after Exodus?
>> You know what the book of Leviticus is
about?
>> The book of Leviticus is about the work
of the priest in cleansing his people
from their sins. That's very interesting
because Christ, the second Adam, was
also drawn out of waters, goes into the
wilderness for 40 days, returns to
deliver his people, and then begins the
work of cleansing his people from their
sins.
>> What book comes after Leviticus?
>> Very interesting. You know what the book
of Numbers is about? The book of Numbers
is about Moses leading the 12 and
calling 70.
Well, that's interesting BECAUSE JESUS,
THE SECOND ADAM, goes is drawn out of
water, goes into the wilderness for 40
days, returns to deliver his people,
begins the work of cleansing them from
their sins, and also calls 12 and
ordains 70.
>> What book comes after numbers?
Deuteronomy.
>> Well, that's interesting because the
book of Deuteronomy is actually Moses's
final sermon. At the end of that book,
he calls together the 12 tribes. He
repeats the covenant. They sing a song,
and then he goes out alone to die by
himself. But he dies, is buried, and
resurrected.
>> [laughter]
>> That's pretty interesting
>> BECAUSE JESUS, THE SECOND ADAM, WHO WAS
DRAWN out of waters, who goes into the
wilderness for 40 days, returns to
deliver his people, uh does THE WORK OF
CLEANSING THEM FROM THEIR SINS, CALLS
12, ORDAINS 70, also gather the 12 at
the end of his ministry,
repeats the covenant, THEY SING A SONG,
AND HE GOES OUT ALONE TO die by himself.
But he dies, is buried, and resurrected.
>> Yeah. Who would have thought?
>> Wait, what?
What book comes after Deuteronomy?
>> Joshua. Very interesting. The book of
Joshua is about a man who leads, who
brings down a nation with a loud shout.
Just as Jesus Christ, the second Adam,
who is drawn out of waters, goes into
the wilderness uh for 40 days, returned
to deliver his people, does the work of
cleansing their sins, calls 12, ordained
70, gathers them together, repeats the
song, repeats the covenant, GOES OUT TO
DIE. WHEN HE DIES, he brings down the
KINGDOM OF SATAN WITH A LOUD SHOUT, "It
is
>> finished."
>> That's pretty interesting.
But there's more
>> because there's another book that comes
after the book of Joshua. What book is
that?
>> Judges.
>> Judges. Very interesting. You know what
the book of Judges is about? The book of
Judges is about the 12 tribes going
forward to conquer even though they no
longer have a physical leader. Very
interesting because after the death,
BURIAL AND RESURRECTION OF JESUS, THE
EARLY church who now NO LONGER HAS A
physical leader like they did in Jesus
Joshua
>> NOW GOES FORWARD CONQUERING IN THE name
of Christ.
>> That's pretty interesting.
>> What book comes after Josh after uh
Judges?
>> Pretty interesting. You know what the
book of Ruth is about? The book of Ruth
is about
the book of Hebrews is I'm sorry. The
book of Ruth is about a gentile woman
with a Hebrew mother-in-law.
>> This gentile woman, you know what she's
doing?
>> She is working in the field bringing in
the sheav.
AND BY THE WAY, BOAZ, WHO WAS A TYPE OF
CHRIST, IS LOOKING AT THAT WOMAN LIKE,
"Who is that lady in the field?"
>> Oh, no.
Who is that woman in the field?
Oh, man. Let me try it on this side.
Let's see. Who is that woman working IN
THE FIELD? I'M ATTRACTED TO THAT WOMAN
working in the field.
>> That's the kind of woman that Jesus
likes.
a woman, a church,
>> working in the field, bringing in the
seeds. And by the way, she says of HER
HEBREW MOTHER-IN-LAW, "YOUR GOD will be
my God."
>> Very interesting.
>> But what comes after the book of Ruth?
>> First Samuel. That's interesting. You
know what the book of First Samuel is
about? The book of First Samuel, and by
the way, we're going somewhere with
this. Okay,
>> there's a point here. The book of 1
Samuel is about a nation, the Israelite
nation, who came up with a really crazy
idea. They decided that they were going
TO REJECT THEIR HIGH PRIEST SAMUEL to
have a king rule over them instead.
>> And this king WOULD USURP THE AUTHORITY
OF THE PRIESTHOOD.
>> IN OTHER WORDS, THIS KING WOULD BRING
TOGETHER IN A SENSE CHURCH and state.
Very interesting
>> because after the church had been
working for some for some time in the
field and doing their thing, they did
something very interesting. They
rejected their high priest Jesus Christ
for a man named Constantine
>> WHO DECIDED TO JOIN CHURCH. AND WOW,
THAT'S VERY IT'S ALMOST LIKE THIS
HISTORY is paralleling the Old
Testament. Amen.
>> Now, beloved, after 1 Samuel, you have 2
Samuel. You have 1 and 2 Kings. You have
1 AND 2 CHRONICLES, WHICH ALL detail
Israel's apostasy,
>> which by the way led them to be taken
captive by a kingdom named mystery.
[laughter]
>> Wow.
Why? that parallels the 1260
years.
Who would have thought that from Genesis
to 2 Chronicles
would be in shadow form the great
controversy as we have understood it in
the book the great controversy.
Wait, what?
But wait,
there's more.
You see after 2 Chronicles remember 2
Chronicles would symbolically bring us
down to what year? 17 98 end of the 1260
years. All right. SO SO PART HERE DON'T
DON'T JUMP AHEAD of me. Just think now
whatever book comes next must HAVE IF
WE'RE GOING ALONG THE LINE MUST HAVE
SOME significance to some major events
THAT WOULD HAPPEN AFTER 1798. So I have
a question for you. What book comes
after 2 Chronicles?
>> Ezra.
You know, we learned a little bit
earlier that there were three decrees,
>> proclamations given in the book of Ezra.
>> Y'all are not feeling me.
>> Three decrees.
Check this out.
>> The first decree
was to bring attention to the sanctuary.
Under that first decree, we are told
that 50,000 people left Babylon to go do
this work. Do you want to know how many
people came out of the fallen churches
of Babylon when the message began to be
preached?
50,000.
>> You can check it out in the book, The
Great Controversy.
>> All right, I'm going to be silent with
you because we are so excited right now.
[laughter]
Because silence is the new excitement.
>> The second decree was against the
enemies of God's people.
>> Just as the second angel's message is
against Babylon,
>> it was the third decree that said,
"Okay, you can now BECOME YOUR OWN
AUTONOMOUS POWER. you a and this was not
just the building OF THE TEMPLE BUT ALSO
THE building of the city and the
rebuilding of everything that belonged
to Jerusalem just as the third angels
under the third angel's message the
seventh day Adventist church was formed
>> that's the book of Ezra
>> now what book comes after Ezra
The fourth
>> decree.
>> Oh wow.
You see beloved Nehemiah uh was to
finish the WORK THAT HAD BEGUN UNDER THE
FIRST THREE DECREES. BUT LISTEN
CAREFULLY. The people of God, the Jews
HAVE BECOME SO uh hh uh discouraged in
the work. THEY HAVE BECOME CAUGHT UP
WITH WITH MAKING THEIR OWN houses
>> and doing their own thing that THEY LET
THE WORK OF GOD FALL BY THE WAYSIDE.
>> And it TOOK NEHEMIAH WHEN NEHEMIAH HEARD
THIS WAIT 13 years later and the WORK IS
NOT DONE. NEHEMIAH WAS MOVED BY THE
SPIRIT OF GOD TO SAY, "NO, SOMETHING'S
GOT TO BE DONE. WE HAVE TO FINISH THE
WORK. WE HAVE TO GET IT TOGETHER."
>> BELOVED, it's been 172 years, I think,
since 1844.
>> Praise God for the work that has been
done under the three angels messages. My
beloved, I believe that a fourth angel,
>> a fourth decree
>> must be sounded
>> in order for the work to be finished.
>> But beloved, the sad news is this.
>> We have paused
>> the story.
We have paused
the story.
We are stuck between Ezra
>> and Nehemiah.
>> We have PAUL'S A STORY BECAUSE WE'VE GOT
LIVES TO LIVE. YOU KNOW,
>> I mean, YOU CAN'T EXPLAIN TO BE ALL
ABOUT THE GOSPEL. I'VE GOT TO FEED MY
KIDS and I, you know, we got to we got
to kind of live
>> in the wilderness.
You see beloved in the in the in OLD
TESTAMENT THE CHILDREN OF ISRAEL THERE
WERE SOME WHO WERE LOOKING FORWARD TO
GETTING OUT OF THE WILDERNESS BUT THERE
WERE OTHERS WHO WERE JUST LIKE YOU KNOW
WE JUST need to make our home here
because man is taking so long you know
so we need to provide an education for
our kids and we need to you know we just
need to make a living in the wilderness
>> beloved are we seeking to make a living
in the wilderness or are we still
believing that Jesus is returning and
wanting to lead us into the promised
land
>> I'm I'm not saying don't live. I'M JUST
SAYING REMEMBER THAT OUR PRIORITY must
be that Jesus is returning. And I don't
believe that's our priority right now.
We have paused the story to fulfill our
own desires.
>> That's right.
>> The story, beloved, is on pause. And one
thing I hate about good stories
>> is when they get put on pause.
It's time to unpause.
>> It's time to unpause. Listen, beloved,
as we study the book of Nehemiah, we
learn that Nehemiah was a man who was so
moved by the spirit of God. He was
listen, he wasn't a pastor. He wasn't a
preacher. He was a cup bearer. AND
NEHEMIAH SAID, "I WILL GO UP AND FINISH
THE WORK."
WHAT we need in this time
>> are more Nehemiah's.
>> You see, beloved, listen to me. The
fourth angel's message is nothing more
than the outpouring of the Holy Spirit.
>> In Revelation 18, that angel is
described as as as coming down and
having a and having the earth lightened
with its glory.
>> And then it CAUSED PEOPLE OUT OF
BABYLON. But listen to me guys, the
message is not so much come out of
Babylon to Babylon.
>> The message is the glory.
>> Oh yeah. [laughter]
It's the glory that leads PEOPLE OUT OF
BABYLON.
>> It's not come out of Babylon. They'll
just be like why [laughter]
COME OUT OF BABYLON DOESN'T DO ANY GOOD.
WE HAVE TO HAVE THE GLORY.
>> And the glory, IT'S THE GLORY OF CHRIST.
SO I GOT A QUESTION FOR YOU. WHERE is
the glory of Christ?
>> THAT'S WHY ISAIAH 55 SAYS, "AS THE RAIN
COMETH down
from heaven,"
Yeah.
>> IT SAYS, "MY WORD SHALL GO FORTH AND NOT
RETURN UNTO ME VOID." NOTICE HOW THE
WORD is likened onto rain.
>> IN DEUTERONOMY, THE BIBLE SAYS, "MY
DOCTRINE SHALL DROP AS THE RAIN UPON THE
GRASS."
>> In other words, beloved, THE THE
OUTPOURING OF THE HOLY SPIRIT IS a
message and a mission.
>> What is the message? The message is
Christ and him crucified.
>> Because Christ and him crucified is the
glory of God. When we look upon the
cross, all the glory,
>> what caused people,
>> remember it was Cyrus drying up the deep
that led people out of Babylon.
>> Oh, no.
Cyrus drying up the deep pointed to
Christ on the cross.
>> So, how do WE LEAD PEOPLE OUT OF
BABYLON? Very simple. Show them Christ
crucified. Show them Christ. Show them
the angel sitting on the tomb saying,
"Look, Christ's death allows you to go
free." When we make Christ and him
crucified the center of our doctrines,
>> when we make, see, this is the
>> look.
>> You want to know what's going to happen
when the Holy Spirit is poured out? You,
the grass, cuz you're the grass. The
rain falls on the grass. Amen.
>> You are the grass.
>> And when the rain falls on the grass,
the people of God are going to start
opening the Bible and they're going to
begin to see things that are so powerful
and so amazing that when they go and
open, they're going to get heartburn.
And let me tell you something for those
How many of you are shy?
How many of you are afraid of public
speaking?
Do you know what my greatest fear is?
Public speaking. [laughter]
When I came here from Jamaica as a
child, 5 years old, everyone laughed at
my accent. And as a result, I developed
an intense fear of public speaking. I
would not speak. I would stand up in
front of people and you could see the
paper shake in the classroom. I was,
this is up until college.
>> And then something happened to me.
>> I got heartburn.
>> And beloved, let me tell you something.
When you get heartburn,
>> That's right. When you get heartburn,
heartburn overpowers fear.
>> Heartburn overpowers shyness.
>> THAT'S WHY GOD IS TRYING TO GET US ON
FIRE. HE'S SAYING, "LOOK, IF I CAN JUST
GET THEM TO FOCUS ON me in the
scriptures, they will have heartburn."
And it WAS HEARTBURN THAT SENT THE
DISCIPLES TO THE upper room and that led
to the outpouring of the Holy Spirit.
AMEN.
>> SO GOD IS TRYING TO POUR OUT HIS SPIRIT
UPON HIS PEOPLE and and and and and it
is by LOOKING AND FINDING CHRIST in the
scripture that we will have a message so
powerful that the people in Babylon will
hear it and come out.
>> It's not only a message, beloved, it is
a mission.
>> You see, the Bible tells us that those
that remember what was Nehemiah's work
to repair the breach.
Isaiah 58 tells US VERY CLEARLY THAT
THOSE WHO HONOR THE SABBATH WILL BE
CALLED THE REPAIRERS OF THE BREACH.
>> But beloved, please listen to me. Many
Seventh Day Adventists have never kept
the Sabbath.
>> Because if YOU LOOK AT HOW THE SABBATH
IS TO BE KEPT, THE BIBLE SAYS THE
SABBATH IS TO BE A DAY OF MERCY.
MEANING, NO, NO, NO, NO, NO. Not meaning
that Sabbath you go to church, you hear
the sermon, you say, "Praise the Lord."
You have potluck, you go home, you go to
sleep. That's not the Sabbath.
According to God, the Sabbath is I go to
church, I hear the sermon, after the
sermon, I I I wonder, okay, who is in
need of being delivered? Who is in need
of clothing? Who is in need of food? who
is in need of ministry, who is bound by
wickedness. Read the text. The Bible
says that this day was meant to be a day
to relieve the oppressed, to undo the
band of wickedness. AND AT 7TH DAY
ADVENTIST, WE SPEND TOO MUCH time in
church on Sabbath.
>> Y'all not feeling me?
>> You see, BELOVED, ON SABBATH, WE ARE
LOCKED AWAY FROM THE WORLD.
>> WAIT, WHAT?
>> What if? Check this out. WHAT IF ON
SABBATH WE WERE OUT THERE IN the world?
>> WHAT IF ON SABBATH WE WERE OUT THERE
BLESSING PEOPLE IN NEED? I'M NOT TALKING
ABOUT BREAKING the Sabbath. So don't
just just just don't oh pastor. That's
not what I'm talking about.
>> I'm talking about ministering to
people's needs ON THE SABBATH. WHAT if
your community knew, man, I love when
Sabbath comes around because those
Adventists,
those Adventists, they are out
ministering to people. they are out are
reaching out to the community to see
what their needs are and how they can
help them and how they can assist them.
What if the what if the 7th Day
Adventist Church decided every Sabbath
is going to be a day of mercy? We are
going to find ways to bless people.
We're going to come up with creative
ways to bless people and so that they
can know that the Sabbath is designed as
a love gift from the God of heaven.
>> Do you realize what that would do to the
world? Do you realize what that would do
to us?
>> Yeah. You see, the message [music] and
the mission changes the character.
>> The message and the mission changes the
character.
And beloved, God is waiting for us to
get that.
>> Amen.
>> So watch this. What book comes after
Nehemiah?
>> Esther.
Interesting. You know what the book of
Esther is about?
The book of Esther is about a death
decree
man
>> GIVEN AGAINST THE PEOPLE OF GOD who
refuse TO KEEP THE LAWS OF THE
GOVERNMENT.
>> But beloved, listen to me. ESTHER WILL
NOT COME ABOUT UNTIL NEHEMIAH HAS BEEN
ACCOMPLISHED.
>> So why are you running to the
wilderness? Okay. Now,
>> who's looking for you? Nobody.
[laughter]
>> YOU KNOW WHY NOBODY'S LOOKING FOR YOU?
CUZ YOU'RE NOT MAKING any noise.
>> You're not making any noise. Beloved,
listen to me. Nehemiah,
when he went to his people, he said,
"COME ON. WE GOT TO FINISH THIS WALL AND
WE GOT TO FINISH IT TOGETHER. WE HAVE A
MISSION. LET'S GO GET THIS MISSION.
LET'S GO DO THIS. BUT WE HAVE TO DO IT
TOGETHER. WE HAVE TO GET IT TOGETHER.
>> Not feel
WE HAVE TO GET IT.
>> BUT TOGETHER,
>> we got to get it together.
>> WE HAVE TO GET IT, BELOVED. NOT ONE HERE
AND ONE THERE. WE HAVE TO GET IT
TOGETHER.
>> God is calling his PEOPLE TO GO
ACCOMPLISH THE mission together.
What book comes after Esther?
>> Oh yeah. Isn't Job about a man who goes
through a time of trouble when it
appears that God has stepped back and
forsaken him?
>> Isn't that what's going to happen at the
very end of time?
>> By the way, the book of Esther, man, I'm
running out of time.
Do you know that the book of Esther is
about uh uh remember who's the guy?
Remember Hmon
>> how Hmon was like hey you know what
everyone bows down to me but there was
one guy that wouldn't bow down to him
and that was Mori
>> because Mori just wouldn't bow
>> and so Hmon was like well because Morai
won't bow to go after his people.
>> You do realize that Satan
had someone that wouldn't bow to him?
>> Jesus. And because Jesus wouldn't bow to
him, you know what he says? He says,
"I'm going after his people.
>> I'm going after his people."
>> And so, beloved, Job points to a people
who will go through a time of trouble.
What book when you're going through a
time of trouble? What is the book that
most people read?
>> That's right.
>> The Psalms is about David on his run
from his enemy. And and the PSALMS SHOWS
DAVID'S CRY, "LORD, DELIVER ME FROM MY
ENEMIES."
WHAT COMES NEXT ARE THE BOOKS OF
ECCLESIASTES and Proverbs. And beloved,
THOSE BOOKS TELL US HOW GOD'S PEOPLE
MUST HAVE WISDOM. Do you think we're
going to need wisdom at the end of time?
Is there a strange woman that God's
people will need to avoid at the end of
time? Absolutely. Proverbs 31, read
about it. These women who caused the
kings to be drunk by alcohol.
>> What book comes after Proverbs?
>> Song of Solomon.
>> Yeah. Jesus is going to come for his
ride.
No yeah yeah the bridegroom
will come for his bride.
>> BELOVED WHO WOULD HAVE THOUGHT THAT THIS
IS THE STORY OF THE BIBLE. HAVE we
missed it?
>> You know what comes after Solomon Song
of Solomon? The major prophets. You know
they all talked about the coming of the
of the second coming of Christ and the
setting up of the millennial kingdom.
They talked about the destruction of the
enemies of God's people. And then the
minor prophets all talk about the
justice of God's judgment because during
the millennium, guess what? God's
justice will be vindicated.
>> And interestingly enough, the book of
the the the Old Testament ends with the
book of Malachi, which ends with the
wicked becoming ASHES UNDER THE SOULS OF
OUR FEET. Who would have thought
>> THAT THE ENTIRE OLD Testament is the
great controversy
>> as we have understood it in the book the
great controversy.
>> Who would have thought?
>> Who would have thought? And then
beloved, when that is all done, Christ
will truly be with us.
>> Matthew 1:21.
>> He will truly be with us. That's what
the gospels talk about. THEN THERE WILL
BE ONE LANGUAGE AND ALL GOD'S PEOPLE
will be united. The book of Acts.
>> THEN JEWS AND GENTILES FROM EVERYWHERE,
ROME, GALATIA, EPHESIA, PHILIPPIA, ALL
OVER THE the Jew, the the people OF ALL
DIFFERENT NATIONS AND NATIONALITIES AND
AND TONGUES WILL ALL COME TOGETHER,
BELOVED, TO behold the ever unfolding
revelation of Jesus Christ through all
eternity. We just heard the story
>> of the entire Bible
>> from Genesis
>> to Revelation.
>> Have we missed the story?
>> I have one more thing to share with you
and 2 minutes and 48 seconds to do it.
>> Jesus Jesus is a symbol of his church.
>> His church is to follow him wherever he
goes. Amen.
>> Jesus was born. There was a birth of the
New Testament church. Yes,
>> Jesus was baptized. There was a baptism
of the New Testament church at
Pentecost. Yes, Jesus went into the
wilderness. The early church would go
into the wilderness for 1260 years. Yes.
>> Jesus after he comes out of the
wilderness, one of the first things he
does IS HE CLEANSES THE TEMPLE.
>> JUST AS AFTER 1798, THE NEW GOD'S CHURCH
WOULD PARTICIPATE IN THAT IN THAT
PROCESS OF THE TEMPLE being cleansed.
wilderness ends 1798 cleansing of the
temple begins 1844 do you know that when
Jesus was cleansing the temple that
first time after he came out of the
wilderness the Jews said 406 years we've
been building this temple will you raise
it up again in 3 days do you know that
if you take 46 years and add it to 1798
>> you get 1844 for.
>> Are you serious? But there's one more
thing that the Lord did right then and
there. Same time, he turned water into
wine at a wedding feast.
Water into wine. And the men tasting the
water said, "Ah, you saved the best wine
for last."
Beloved, Babylon is giving the world
wine right now.
God's people
have the best wine.
>> It's time to go forth
>> with that wine.
>> It's time to go forth with that. It's
time to unpause.
>> I want to make an appeal. I'm going to
ask you to stand. I'm not going to ask
you to come down. Don't stand. Don't
stand. Wait for my appeal. My appeal is
You're your Amen.
STANDING BEFORE THE APPEAL. THAT'S WHAT
I LIKE.
>> We need the spirit of Nehemiah.
>> You need to realize it's not about the
pastor doing it or this guy doing it or
that guy doing it. It's about me.
>> It's about me. God needs me to be like a
Nehemiah. And today you're saying,
"Lord, that's it. I unpause. God's been
calling me to be baptized. I've been
putting it on on pause. I am unpausing.
God has called me to preach. I've put
that on pause. I AM UNPAUSING TONIGHT.
GOD, YOU USE ME HOW YOU want to be you.
How you want me to be used. Use me,
Lord. I officially come unpaused.
>> If that's your desire, I'm going to ask
you to stand to your feet.
>> Heavenly Father,
>> help us to unpause.
>> Amen.
>> Forgive us for putting your story on
pause
>> while we have lived our lives and done
our wills. Yes.
>> Please Lord, fill us with your spirit.
Rain upon us. Lord, open our eyes that
we may behold Christ in all the
scriptures.
>> And Father, help us not only to preach
the message, but to live the message.
>> Father, help us to begin to truly keep
the Sabbath. And Lord, as these two
things are combined, may the walls be
rebuilt so that you can finally come
again. Thank you Lord for telling us the
story of the Bible in Jesus name we
pray. Amen.
>> You may be seated.
>> Praise the Lord.
>> Tim, why don't we do a little chorus and
all of you there help us. Something
about that